-
-=
-= L
-= LU
-= LUO
-= LUO M
-= LUO MA
-= LUO MAD
-= LUO MADE
-= LUO MADE D
-= LUO MADE DV
-= LUO MADE DVD
-= LUO MADE DVD =
-= LUO MADE DVD =-
「1991年，波斯灣戰爭剛結束」
要不要開槍？
Are we shooting?
什麼？
What?
我們到底要不要開槍打人？
Are we shooting people or what?
我們要開槍嗎？
Are we shooting?
我剛不是這樣問你嗎？
That's what I』m asking you!
答案是什麼？
What's the answer?
我不知道，所以我才要問
I don't know the answer!
That's what I』m trying to find out!
給我一點口香糖
我剛已經給過你了
-Give me some gum.
-I already gave you some.
我看到你眼睛裡有一粒沙子
但弄不出來
I can see a grain of sand in there.
I just can't get it out.
這傢伙似乎有帶武器
I think this guy has a weapon!
果然沒錯
Yeah, he does!
恭喜你，你打死了個中東鬼
Whoa! Congratulations,
my man, you shot yourself a raghead.
沒想到在這場戰爭中
居然還能看到有人被殺
Dag. Didn't think I'd get to see
anybody shot in this war.
幫我照張相
Aw, take my picture.
奪寶大作戰
I just want to celebrate another day of livin'
I just want to celebrate another day of life
I put my faith in the people
But the people let me down
So I turned the other way
And I carry on anyhow
That's why I'm telling you
I just want to celebrate
Another day of livin'
軍營中充滿了歡欣熱鬧的音樂
大家都士氣高昂
Spirits are high,
and the music is boisterous...
這些年輕士兵…
該死的，等一會兒
...as these young troops--
Shit, hold on a second. Okay.
軍營中充滿了歡欣熱鬧的音樂
大家都士氣昂揚…
Music is high, and the spirits
are soaring as these--
我剛剛是不是說「昂揚」？
Did I just say "soaring"?
How did it sound?
聽起來如何？
他們說美軍藉著這次任務
來驅趕越戰帶來的陰影
They say you exorcised the ghost of
Vietnam with a clear, moral imperative.
我們解放了科威特
We liberated Kuwait.
If I had to start again
With just my children and my wife
I would thank my lucky stars
To be living here today
Because the flag
Still stands for freedom
And they can't take that away
And I'd gladly stand up next to you
And defend her still today
'Cause there ain't no doubt
I love this land
God bless the U.S.A.
「特洛拜隆
最近喜獲麟兒」
It was you that chose your due
You built a maze you can't get through
I tried to help you all I can
But I can't do nothing for you, man
I can't do nothing for you, man
-Go lean on shells
-Answer man
I can't do nothing for you, man
「康拉德維克
他極為羨慕特洛拜隆」
-Go lean on shells
-Answer man
I can't do nothing for you, man
You jumped out of the jelly into a jam
Make you love the wrong instead of right
Not a thief cat burglar through the night
The cop told your girl her name was Shirl
About a rooftop crime to steal her pearls
Oozy down the bullets in the gun
英勇的戰士…
Trained warrior! Trained warrior!
蓋特少校…
Trained warrior! Oh, my God!
Major Gates, Major Gates, Major Gates!
「艾奇蓋特
剩兩周就可退伍」
愛德安娜採訪到什麼新聞？
What's Adriana got?
還不是戰勝慶功的那些鏡頭
Just the celebration story.
就這樣？
這種新聞根本是曇花一現
That's it? That story's evaporating.
伊拉克戰俘的新聞
也是曇花一現
The Iraqi POW story's evaporating.
我要採訪伊拉克將黃金
歸還科威特的新聞
I still have my gold story, though.
Returning the gold to Kuwait.
你對那件事瞭解多少？
What do you know about that?
他們說黃金藏在某個碉堡裡面
They think it's in
some bunker somewhere.
Oh, oh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
怎麼了，上校？
我正要問你
相同的問題呢，少校
-What's going on?
-I was about to ask you the same thing.
你說過他是前特種部隊的一員
他會好好照顧我
真是一派胡言
You said he was former Delta, he'd take
great care of me. What a bunch of bullshit.
讓我來處理，好嗎？
她難道沒有自己的護衛嗎？
-Let me handle this.
-Doesn't she have an escort?
當然有，她就在這裡
你幫她找一個能讓她搞的護衛
-Of course she does. She's right here.
- Find her someone she can fuck...
這樣她就不會來染指
我的帖身保鏢了
你講話小心點
-...so she'll leave my escort alone.
- That's unnecessary.
我不希望他把我採訪到的新聞
洩漏給其他的記者
I don't want him going to other
reporters and giving away my stories.
你根本沒採訪到什麼新聞嘛
你不可以四處張揚
-You don't have any stories.
-You don't tell people that!
看看你自己變成什麼德性
Look at you.
Look at what's become of you.
沒錯，但我至少還穿著衣服
Yes, look at me.
I've got my clothes on! I』m dressed!
「愛德安娜克魯茲
五度與艾美獎擦身而過」
沒錯，但你已經人老珠黃
But I will say you are old, Adriana.
我不想為這等狗屎事煩心
少校
你懂不懂？
I really don't need this shit, major.
You understand me?
這是一場媒體戰爭
你最好搞清楚狀況
Yeah.
-This is a media war. A media war...
...and you better get onboard!
我們明天要好好談談
我要好好的修理你
We'll talk about this tomorrow.
I』m gonna straight you out!
照張相
Take a picture!
再照一張
One more!
帥斃了
-Very handsome.
-All right.
So please stay off my back
Or I will attack
And you don't want that
拜隆，你真是神槍手
Yeah!
-Good shot, Barlow.
別鬧了
Hey, enough!
上尉要來了
Captain's coming!
「契夫艾吉
為了逃離底特律而從軍」
你們最好快一點
他現在就來了
You better move your butts.
He's coming right now.
該死的，這些酒是哪兒來的
快處理掉
Goddamn it! Where the hell did this
booze come from? Hey, get rid of it!
我們明天還要繼續處理
伊拉克人戰俘…
We gotta take more Iraqi prisoners
tomorrow! Tomorrow!
把彈夾拿下來
把武器丟到左邊的地上
Remove the magazine from your weapon.
Sling your weapon over
your left shoulder, muzzle down.
雙手高舉過頭
Have both arms raised above your head.
請跟著領隊士兵
慢慢的朝著多國部隊前進
Approach the multinational force's
position slowly...
...with the lead soldier
holding this document...
將文宣高舉過頭
這樣做就不會被殺死
...above his head. If you do this,
you will not die.
根據國際慣例
You will be processed
as prisoners of war...
我們會提供戰服，食物，衣服
和遮風避雨棲身之處
...provided food, shelter and clothing...
...and be treated according to the guidelines
provided by the Geneva Convention.
Do not resist.
這樣做就會得到這些
If you do this, you get this.
只要投降，就有吃有睡
If you surrender,
you will get food and shelter. Okay?
沒事的，沒有人會傷害你們的
不要緊張
Everything is cool.
Nobody's gonna hurt you. Just relax.
先生，麻煩你把頭巾拿下來
Sir, you're gonna have to
take the turban off as well.
你有沒有在科威特
強暴或折磨任何人？
Did you rape and torture anyone
in Kuwait, Abdul?
那你呢，你這個狗娘養的？
What about you, motherfucker?
你把他們嚇壞了，把槍收起來
你這樣會闖禍的
Hey, hey. You're making them hysterical.
Stop pointing that. You'll get us in trouble.
別緊張，請各位趴在地上
Just relax. We want everybody facedown.
-Come on.
-Get down.
聽不懂英文嗎，渾蛋？
Take these things-- Hey,
no comprende English, motherfucker?
你有什麼毛病啊？
What is your fucking problem?
拜託你拿出專業素養
你把他們嚇壞了
Act in a more
professional manner, please.
我也想要保持專業素養
但他不肯拿掉頭巾
I wanna be professional.
He wouldn't take his rags off.
在一旁學著點吧
對不起，先生
Pay attention to how it's done.
Excuse me, sir.
請你像其他的毛巾頭一樣
寬衣解帶，好嗎？
Listen. Sir, we're gonna need you to
disrobe like all the other towelheads, okay?
我也不希望事情演變成這樣
把他的衣服剝下來
I hate to see it come to this.
Strip him down.
Come on, motherfucker.
把你的衣服脫掉
Take your fucking clothes off.
快點
Come on.
特洛，快過來看
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Troy. Troy.
Troy, come here. Check this out.
快來看，簡直是變態透了
Freaky thing here, possibly.
那傢伙的屁股裡塞了一些文件
There's a document in that guy's ass.
有狀況了
We got a classified situation.
這張紙是不是被他吃下去了？
You think he ate it?
如果是被吃下去的
不會這麼完整
No, it wouldn't come out
perfect like that if he ate it.
把它拉出來，士兵
-Pull it out, private.
- Back off! Back off!
拉出來
Pull it out.
我從軍不是為了
把手伸到大男人屁股裡去
Man, I didn't join the Army
to pull paper out of people's asses.
百分之百不是
No, sir. Not what I signed up for.
Aw-- Aw--
Ugh!
打開來看
Open it up.
你只給我一隻手套
You only gave me one glove.
我只有一隻手套
但你一定要把它打開來
Sorry, I only have one,
but you have to open it.
我的軍階比你高
你要聽我的話
That's how the chain of command works.
Ugh.
是什麼？
What is it?
不知道，反正很重要就是了
It』s important enough
to squeeze your cheeks for.
你要讓她心甘情願的報導
我們要她報導的事
You're supposed to make her
feel good about stories we want...
而不要去挖
我們不想要讓人知道的事
...not push stories we don't want.
你不可以丟下她
去上另一個記者
You don't walk away from her
and go screw another journalist.
我本來就不想
擔任這個任務，朗
I never wanted this job, Ron.
你在伊拉克的任務結束了
Your work in Iraq was over. Done.
我想要幫你忙
如果你處理得宜的話
I』m trying to help you out.
If you play your cards right...
讓你在國內媒體界找份好差事
...maybe she'll hook you up
with the media at home.
去他的好差事
-Fuck that.
-Fuck that?
去他的？你以後打算怎麼辦？
Where you going?
你未來一片光明
You got your star clinched.
你無法陞官
難不成都是我的錯？
Oh, so now it's my fault that
you plateaued a long time ago?
我甚至不知道
我們在這裡做了什麼
少來這套…
-I don't even know what we did here.
-Don't start.
告訴我我們在伊拉克
做了什麼？
Just tell me what we did here, Ron.
你想佔領伊拉克
重演越戰舊事嗎？
You wanna occupy Iraq
and do Vietnam all over again?
這就是你想要的嗎？
Is that your brilliant idea?
去他的，我反正要退休了
-Fuck it, I』m retiring anyway.
在你退休之前
你仍然是美國軍人
-Until you do, you're an Army officer.
你仍然要照顧那名記者
別搞砸了
You're still taking care of
that reporter, so do it right.
Let's move this now!
你已經洗了一千次了，別洗了
Come on, you've washed your hands
a thousand times.
誰知道那傢伙屁股裡
有什麼寄生蟲
Lord knows what vermin
live in the butt of a dune coon.
你為何讓這傢伙
當你的跟屁蟲？
Why do you let this cracker
follow you around, man?
他沒問題的
他是從達拉斯的孤兒院來的
He's got no high school.
He's from a group home in Dallas.
他沒念高中，很可憐的
-He doesn't know better.
-Don't say that.
別四處宣揚嘛
就算他是從約翰尼斯堡來的
我也不管
I don't care if he's from Johannesburg.
我不希望聽到任何人
說這些有種族歧視意味的話
I don't wanna hear "dune coon" or
"sand nigger" from him or anybody.
上尉不是也有說嗎？
Captain uses those terms.
康拉德，你可以改稱他們為
「毛巾頭」或是「騎駱駝的」
Look, the point is, "towelhead" and
"camel jockey" are good substitutes.
完全正確
對不起
-Exactly.
- I apologize.
你們這些親阿拉伯反伊拉克的
作風搞的我暈頭轉向
A little confusing with all this pro-Saudi,
anti-Iraqi type language and all that.
你拿到高空照片了沒？
Did you get the aerials?
這些照片是哪兒來的？
How'd you get those?
契夫自有辦法
叫華特把守好門口
Chief is hooked up.
-Hey. Keep Walter on that door.
把夜視鏡拿掉
Would you take
those fucking things off?
我從來沒有戴過夜視鏡
I never got to use night vision.
夜視鏡在白天沒有用
They do not work during the day.
還是有點用的
Yeah, they kind of work.
你到外面去好讓契夫研究這張
伊拉克屁眼地圖
Just stand outside so Chief
can translate my Iraqi ass map, okay?
Okay.
你現在打算跟我合作了嗎？
Are you ready to work with me now?
是的
I』m ready to work with you.
很好，因為我得到一個
驚人的線報
Good. Because I've got an amazing lead.
地圖藏在那傢伙的屁股裡
不是這樣的
-It was in his ass.
- That's not the real story.
那是怎樣？
圖藏在他的老二里
-What's the real story?
-It was in the guy's dick.
他們用鑷子把圖拔了出來
那是一本薩達姆碉堡圖？
-Had to pull it out with a pair of tweezers.
-A 10-page atlas of Saddam's bunkers?
沒錯，不過很小
就像是吃乖乖送的那種
Yeah. Only real small, like those books
you get in a box of Cracker Jacks.
他們從那傢伙的耳朵裡
把圖拉了出來
They pull it out the guy ear.
他說什麼？
從耳朵拉出來的
-What?
-"Out of his ear."
也許是鼻子
Maybe out the nose.
他到底在說什麼？
鼻子
-What's he talking about?
-"The nose."
告訴我是哪個部位？
你讓我來問
-What body part?
-Let me handle this.
那張圖被縫在他的後腦杓裡
那張圖被縫在他的後腦杓裡？
縫在後腦杓裡
-It was stitched in back of his head.
- Stitched in the back of his head.
他叫什麼名字？
誰？
-The guy's name?
- What guy?
找到圖的人
我不能說
The guy who found it.
放屁，你說過可以告訴我們
抱歉，現在不能說
- I cannot tell you.
- Fuck that!
-You said you could.
-Sorry, not now.
這小子什麼都不知道
- This guy doesn't know shit.
- Adriana, come here.
他什麼都不知道
He doesn't know shit.
聽著，他是法國特種部隊的人
他能幫我們的
Listen to me. This guy is French
Special Forces and he can help us.
他能幫我們？
是的，他是我的朋友
-He can?
-Yes, and he's my friend.
但有你在，他就不會說
But he's not gonna talk to me
if you're around.
你最好別耍我
我沒有
-Better not be fucking with me.
-I』m not.
我這次一定要採訪到這個新聞
你會如願的
-I want the story this time.
-You'll get the story. Okay?
這一定是薩達姆的碉堡
就在卡巴拉和納撒拉間
These have got to be Saddam's
bunkers between Karbala and Nazaria.
裡面有什麼？
What's inside?
根據我們的情報
裡面有畢加索的名畫
新力電器，亞曼尼名牌服飾
勞力士
According to Intel,
Picasso, Sony, Armani, Rolex.
科威特是阿拉伯的首富之區
薩達姆把這裡洗劫一空
Kuwait was like the Arab Beverly Hills.
Saddam jacked them for it.
如果能帶一些
好東西回去就好了
Be nice to bring something home
besides sand fleas.
只要拿到一隻勞力士軍表
我就能買下一棟房子
One gold Rolex would get me a very
nice house outside of Garland.
五隻勞力士就能買一輛
萊瑟斯敞蓬車
Five would get a Lexus convertible.
萊瑟斯不出敞蓬車
才怪
-Lexus doesn't make one.
-Yes, they do.
後面還可以放嬰兒椅
It has room for a kid seat.
永恆有出敞蓬車
-Infiniti has a convertible, not Lexus.
-Wrong.
但萊瑟斯沒有
你錯了
不管怎麼說
上帝讓我們得到這張藏寶圖
我相信我們能夠找到寶藏
Either way, the Lord put this map in
our path. I believe we'll find something.
上帝也賜給我們一條
充滿地雷之路
He could also put a land mine
in our path.
我不這麼認為
我受過聖火洗禮
I don't think so. I've been fire
baptized, and this feels safe.
我覺得應該不會有危險
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
耶穌會指引我的
I have a ring of Jesus fire
to guide my decisions.
你在耍我，對吧？
-Do I look like I』m putting you on?
我像是在耍你嗎？
-You're putting me on, right?
好吧，你說是就是
Okay, ring of Jesus fire.
停
Halt!
不要動，渾蛋
Freeze, motherfucker!
對不起，這邊是閒人勿入
讓開
-Sir, this tent is restricted, sir.
-Get out of my way.
緊急情況…
Sir! Sir!
該死的
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! Goddamn it.
午安，這裡是
直腸外科帳篷嗎？
Good afternoon.
Would this be the proctology tent?
不是，長官
No, sir.
那就是泌尿科帳篷羅
還是神精外科？
Maybe it's a urology tent.
Or the neurology tent.
還是耳鼻喉科？
Or the ear, nose and throat tent.
上尉在開小組會議，長官
Captain's at a staff meeting, sir.
上尉是直腸外科專家嗎？
Captain a proctologist?
什麼是直腸外科專家？
那不重要
-What's a proctologist, sir?
- It doesn't matter.
我不是來找上尉的
我是來找拜隆士官長
I』m not looking for him.
I』m looking for Barlow.
不是有句俗話說
「聞到屎味就離真相不遠」
You're on the path to truth when you smell
shit. Isn』t that what they say, sergeant?
我沒看過你，長官
你是我們隊上的人嗎？
I don't recognize you, sir.
Are you in this division?
不，他是特種部隊的人
He's not from this division.
He's Special Forces.
你們有沒有把這張圖
拿給你們的長官看？
Have you soldiers
presented this map to your captain?
還沒有
Not yet, sir.
我拿去給他
I'll take it to him.
沒這個必要，長官
他是我的直屬長官
我會拿去給他
That's not necessary, sir.
He's my CO. I can take it to him.
別太貪心了
Don't get grabby, sergeant.
他是我們的直屬長官
我得告訴他你把這張圖拿走了
He's our CO, sir.
I'd have to tell him you took it.
這樣做對我們都沒好處
是吧？
That won't do either of us any good,
will it?
是的
No, sir.
坐下
Sit down.
你圖上畫的是什麼？
是碉堡
-What do you see here?
-Bunkers, sir.
碉堡裡放的是什麼東西？
他們從科威特搶來的東西
- What are in them?
- Stuff they stole from Kuwait.
鬼扯，裡面放的是
科威特的金條
Bullshit. I』m talking about
millions in Kuwaiti bullions.
你是說那種雞湯塊嗎？
You mean them little cubes
you put in hot water and make soup?
不是雞湯塊
No, not the little cubes
you put in hot water to make soup.
是金塊
Gold bricks, Conrad.
這是薩達姆從阿拉伯手中偷走的
我再去偷他的東西
一點都不會良心不安
Saddam stole it from the sheiks.
I have no problem stealing it from Saddam.
我認為他應該是把這些金條
分成好幾堆儲藏
My guess is, he's divided these bricks
into several different stashes.
想要從他的軍隊手中
奪走一堆應該不是難事
Just one of these stashes would be easy
for us to take from his deserting army.
只要成功我們這輩子
就可以不用再工作了
That would be enough
to get us out of our day jobs.
除非你們不願意放棄
你們的工作
Unless of course you reservists
are in love with your day jobs.
我沒有工作
I don't really have a day job, sir.
首先我們要確定
這張真的是藏寶圖
First thing we have to do...
...is make sure this is more
than a love letter to an Iraqi.
卡巴拉附近有許多碉堡
It』s a series of bunkers
outside Karbala, sir.
也許吧
我們百分之百確定
Maybe.
-Definitely, sir.
偵察照片已經證實了這一點
The recon photos match.
走著瞧吧
We'll see.
Dag.
咱們特種部隊配備精良
所以才人見人怕
It』s what makes S.F. so badass.
We got the best flashlights.
我看的確是一堆碉堡
東邊還有三個小村莊
Still looks like a series of bunkers.
Three villages a little farther
to the east.
北邊75公里處
應該是65公里
-Seventy-five clicks north.
- More like 65.
這離聯合國部隊很遠
Way north of any allied troops.
簡直是太完美了
離部隊越遠越好
Perfect. We don't want
any troops around.
我們可以開著吉普車
到幼發拉底河河谷去
Yeah. Just us and a Humvee
up by the Euphrates River Valley.
摩西小時候
就是被人丟在那裡的
Where they put Moses in the basket.
那是埃及
That's Egypt.
我們東方三賢人
要去偷這些金條
We three kings be stealing the gold
安靜
Quiet down!
我們的朋友都開保時捷
我一定要迎頭趕上
My friends all drive Porsches
I must make amends
閉嘴，好嗎？
你唱完了沒？
- Hey, just shut up, okay?
- Are you done singing?
地雷怎麼辦，長官？
What about mines, sir?
82軍已經完成掃雷任務
我們不要離開馬路就好
Grid was swept by the 82nd.
We'll stick to the roads.
我們現在只需要弄一部
2，5公噸的卡車就行了
Are we gonna need
a deuce-and-a-half?
不，開吉普車
比較不會引人注目
It』s easier to slip out in a Humvee.
如果我們到找寶藏怎麼辦？
-What if we have a lot to carry?
那就搶一輛伊拉克卡車
這樣萬一被攔下來
也比較不會出事
We'll grab an Iraqi truck.
Better cover if we get stopped.
我們可以說這是我們從
伊拉克軍俘據來的
沒錯
We could always say we captured it.
-That's right.
我們黎明出發
午餐前就可以回來了
沒什麼大不了的
We leave at dawn, back before lunch.
No big deal.
站在外面那小子叫什麼名字？
華特
-What's the guy's name outside?
-Walter.
波羅，進來
-Bolo! Get in here!
-Who's Bolo, sir?
波羅是誰？
是個不知道自己在做什麼的人
Bolo is a guy who
doesn't know what he's doing.
什麼事，長官？
-Yes, sir?
- Want you to get this reporter...
我要你去擺平那個記者
你知道愛德安娜克魯茲
是誰吧？
...off my back.
Know who Adriana Cruz is?
她是NBS的記者
沒錯
-Reporter on NBS, sir.
- That's right.
告訴她我去幫她打探消息
你會帶她來找我
Tell her I』m checking a story
and you're bringing her to meet me.
去伊拉克？
不
In Iraq?
-No.
我會給你一張假地圖
你帶她出去兜兜風
I'll give you a fake copy of this map.
Take her on a ride
that lasts all morning...
但絕對不能靠近那些
卡拉巴村莊
...and goes nowhere near
the villages outside of Karbala.
如果找不到我那是因為
你們迷路了，明白嗎？
When you don't find me, it'll be
because you got lost. Is that clear?
是的
還有其它的問題嗎？
-Yes, sir.
-Any other questions?
特種部隊是不是要割下
敵人的耳朵？
Yeah. Is it true that to be S.F.,
you gotta cut off an enemy's ear?
你制得住他嗎？
我保證沒問題
-Are you able to control him?
-Yes, sir. He'll be fine, I promise.
我們準備明天早上出發
Let's get ready to roll in the morning.
出發羅
All right, here we go, ma'am.
快丟
Pull!
我也要玩
Let me get some, chief.
快丟
Pull!
我丟的比你好
-I gave you a better arc!
- What you talking about?
你在說什麼？
I threw the ball at a higher arc.
我丟的球比較高比較容易打
鬼扯
-Made it easier.
-Bullshit!
黑人不適合當四分衛
比較適合當接球員
Blacks make better receivers
than quarterbacks.
住嘴
Stop speaking.
華倫穆恩是有史以來
最出色的四分衛
Warren Moon is one of
the best in the league.
就算有了華倫穆恩
休士頓隊還是一樣吃癟
Houston's gone nowhere
with Warren Moon.
那倫達卡寧漢呢？
契夫，別說了
-Randall Cunningham?
-Don't get in the mud with him.
要是靠卡寧漢
老鷹隊就進不了超級杯了
Eagles'll never make it to
the Super Bowl with Cunningham.
道格威廉斯不光是讓紅人隊
進入超級杯，而且還贏了
Doug Williams not only took
the Redskins to the Super Bowl...
-...but they won.
-Yeah, so?
那又怎樣？
的確有不少出色的四分衛
是黑人
We can all agree there are many
excellent black quarterbacks.
看看你有多行
Let's see what you can hit.
你這個爛白人
你絕對打不中伊拉克人
Come on, sorry-ass cracker!
You'll never hit no Iraqi!
才怪，我能一槍
轟掉伊拉克人的頭
I'll hit that Iraqi.
I'll blow his fucking head off!
契夫，你別管他
和他辯只會越來越糟
Chief, he talks like that,
ignore him or it'll get worse.
你說的對
不過有時候我實在忍不住
You're right, you're right.
Just can't help myself sometimes.
注意看
Watch this.
Whoa! Unh!
那是怎麼回事？
我在足球上綁了炸藥
-What was that?
- I rigged a football with C4, sir.
你為何那麼做？
Why would you do that?
你自己說只要開的夠遠
就可以開槍取樂
You said we could fire off
some rounds when we left camp.
我說你們可以開幾槍
I said that you could fire a few rounds.
我們根本沒有體驗到
戰爭的刺激
We didn't get to see any action, sir.
你想體驗刺激？
是的
-You wanna see some action?
- Yeah, I do, sir.
你想看的是這些嗎？
Is this what you're after?
美軍在這裡投擲了不少炸彈
We dropped a lot of bombs here.
我們也活埋了許多人
We also buried a lot of guys alive.
我們唯一看到的激烈戰況
是在電視新聞上
除了特洛開槍打死的那個人
The only action we seen was on CNN,
except for that dude Troy shot.
你打中了他的喉嚨？
是的
-Shot him in the neck?
-That's right, sir.
他簡直酷斃了
隔著四百碼就打死了那個人
Fucking badass. I was there.
Fucking took him out at 400 yards.
把他的頭打得半天高
簡直是神槍手
Head popped up 3 feet in the air.
It was a crazy shot, man.
別這麼說
你知不知道被槍打到會怎樣？
You know anything
about gunshot wounds?
不知道
你聽好了
-I don't know.
- Specifically.
如果沒被子彈打死
就很可能會發生敗血症
The worst thing about a gunshot wound,
provided you survive the bullet...
-...is something called sepsis.
-Infection of the blood.
血液感染？
沒錯
假設你腹部中彈
Right. Say a bullet tears into you--
會在體內造成
充滿死亡組織的部位
Creates a cavity of dead tissue.
That cavity...
如果被膽汁或細菌感染的話
你就死定了
...it fills up with bile and bacteria.
You're fucked.
我們這次行動絕對不能開槍
But we're gonna do this
without firing any shots...
為了以防萬一
我們來排演一下
...and just to be sure,
we're gonna do a dry run.
穿好你們的防護衣
So get your suits on.
假設那頭母牛是碉堡外的守衛
We will say that the cow is
a primary guard outside the bunker.
你們的動作一定要快
Pull up fast. Stop short.
而且要侵略性十足，懂嗎？
Move very aggressively. Got it?
懂了
Got it!
開始
Go!
有沒有人受傷？
Who's hurt?
這些都是牛血
It』s all cow.
沒錯，都是牛的血
Yeah, it's all cow.
你們有沒有看到牛頭
被射的半天高？
Kaboom!
Y'all see that cow's head shoot up?
簡直就像卡通一樣，瘋狂極了
Just like a cartoon.
It』s fucking crazy.
你說這裡的地雷
已經被清乾淨了
You said this area was swept for mines.
不是地雷，是集束炸彈
這種炸彈很難找的
Wasn't a mine. It was a cluster bomb.
Very hard to see.
上車吧，我們要出發了
Get in the Humvee.
We're moving on.
Round, round, get around
I get around
Yeah, get around
Ooh, ooh, I get around
Round, round, get around
-I get around
-I get around, yeah
Get around
I get around
-I get around
-Get around, round, round
-From town to town
我們衝進去，別忘了開保險
We go in fast, leave the safeties on.
攻他們個措手不及
Hit them with the blinding power
of American sunshine.
-I』m making real good bread
-Get around, round, round, I get around
I』m gettin' bugged
Driving up and down the same old strip
I gotta find a new place
Where the kids are hip
My buddies and me
Are gettin' real well-known
Yeah, the bad guys know us
And they leave us alone
I get around
碉堡在哪裡？
Where's the bunker?
在那裡
There. No, there!
不，在那裡
Round, round, I get around
-I』m a real cool head
-Get around, round, round, I get around
I』m making real good bread
我們是奉美國總統之命行事
Orders from the president
of the United States of America.
我們是奉美國總統之命行事
Orders from the president
of the United States of America.
退後
-Step aside.
- Get back!
趴在地上
On the ground, right now.
我們是美軍
We are the Army
of the United States of America.
退後
Stay back!
我們是美軍
We are the Army
of the United States of America.
我沒有牛奶喂孩子
No milk! Baby milk!
-Baby milk!
-Let's go.
走吧
我們是來保護各位的
不要害怕，退後
We are here for
your protection and safety.
Stay calm. Lay back. Hey.
退後，快點
Let's go, step aside. Move!
這是美國總統布希的命令
是停火協議的一部份
Orders from President Bush.
Part of the ceasefire agreement.
請你們合作
「這些美國人是創子手
全身沾滿鮮血」
安全了，我們走吧
Clear. Let's move.
我們是美國軍人
- United States military!
我們是美國軍人，全部出去
Everybody out!
我們是來保護各位的
知道嗎？
We are here for your protection
and safety, all right?
趴下去
Hey. Get down on the ground.
Get down on the ground.
美國人來了，我們安全了
我們可以對抗薩達姆
這是美國的命令
Order from the United States.
該死的
Ah. Shit!
再來
Again!
不要動
美國萬歲
Freeze!
-I love the United State of freedom.
我恨薩達姆
-I hate Saddam.
-Yah! Yah!
放開他
-Yah! Yah! Yah!
-Let him go!
沒問題，朋友
No problem, my friend. No problem.
沒問題
No problem.
叫他閉嘴
Tell him to shut up. Be quiet.
我愛美國
I am love United State of freedom.
我也愛美國
I』m love United States of freedom too.
冷靜點，不要說話
我是你們的朋友
- Just calm down and be quiet, okay?
- I am friend. Friend.
我是你們的朋友
I am-- I am friend. I am friend.
你們是來找化學武器的嗎？
-You look for chemical weapon?
- No.
我們是來找黃金的
這裡沒有黃金
-We look for the gold.
-No gold here.
閉嘴
沒有黃金
No gold.
你說什麼？
這裡沒有黃金
- What did you say?
- No gold.
他說這裡沒有黃金
那黃金在哪裡？
- He says there's no gold here.
- Where's the gold?
殺了他
遵命
-Kill him.
-You wanna die?
你想死嗎？
在另一個村莊中的碉堡裡
在另一個碉堡裡？
-Other bunker, other village! Yes.
-Other bunker?
不是這個碉堡，是另一個？
不是這裡
-Not this bunker? Another?
- No. Not this town.
在那裡嗎？
That town? That town?
對，就是那裡
That town! Yes, yes, yes! That town.
我們走吧
Let's go.
打倒薩達姆
你為何對他們丟石頭？
Why you throwing rocks at them?
解放伊拉克
快攔住那輛卡車
這裡不准送東西來
是牛奶
It』s milk.
請送藥來
Please bring us food.
-Please bring medicine.
- Medicine. Medicine.
請幫幫我們
-Please help us.
- Hey, hey. Hey, come on.
別這樣
下車
- We need doctors.
- Off the vehicle!
女士，請你下車
Ma'am, you'll have to step down
from the vehicle.
醫院…
Hospital! Hospital!
食物，我們好餓
We need your help, please.
Food. Food.
把我們的口糧給他們
我們快離開這裡
Give them the M.R.E.s. Let's go!
拿去吧
Take that. Take that.
那個女人的水被士兵搶走了
The soldier's taking the water
away from that woman.
Heads up!
Here you go.
快下去
Look out! Get off!
Hey.
把東西還給那個小男孩
Hey, give that back to the boy!
帶我一起去
-Take me, take me, take me.
- Excuse me. No.
你不能跟我們來
-You can't come with us.
-Please take me. Aah!
冷靜點…
Right here, right now.
剛剛那裡到底發生什麼事？
The fuck was going on back there, major?
平民唾棄士兵，士兵射擊平民
Civilians spitting on soldiers.
Soldiers shooting civilians.
他們根本對我們不屑一顧
Ignoring us like we weren't there.
伊拉克軍隊已經向我們投降了
現在平民才是他們的目標
They surrendered.
Now they're after civilians.
他們為何要炸掉牛奶車？
Why'd they blow up that milk truck?
他們想要餓死那些人
為何？
-Trying to starve the people out.
-Why?
布希叫平民起身反抗薩達姆
Bush told the people
to rise up against Saddam.
他們以為美軍會幫助平民
但事實不然
They thought they had our support,
they don't.
現在平民遭到屠殺
Now they're getting slaughtered.
另一座碉堡在哪裡？
So where's the next bunker?
如果那人說的沒錯
就在離這裡20公里處
About 20 clicks on the map,
according to what that guy said.
不，不是
No, it's not.
那座井有問題
There was something about that well.
哪座井？
村中的那座井
- What well?
- The well in the center of town.
那裡有士兵防守
我打賭下面有地下碉堡
There were soldiers guarding it.
I bet there's a bunker in there.
那傢伙騙我們
The guy lied to us.
黃金就在那裡
It』s back where we came from.
我不能這麼做
Hey, I don't know if I can do this, okay?
Hey! I got a family.
我有妻小
如果在戰爭結束之後
我還被打成殘障
If I shit in a bag for life because
I got shot after the war was over...
那就太荒謬了
...that'd be pretty stupid,
wouldn't it?
人生最重要的是什麼？
What is the most important
thing in life?
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
人生最重要的是什麼？
What's the most important thing?
尊重
這太依靠別人了
-Respect.
- Too dependent on other people.
是愛嗎？
你有點太天真了吧
-What, love?
-A little Disneyland, isn't it?
上帝的旨意
God's will.
很接近了
不然是什麼？
-Close.
- What is it then?
需要
Necessity.
怎麼說？
As in...?
人類會視自己的需要而行動
People do what is most necessary
to them at any given moment.
現在薩達姆的部隊最需要的
就是鎮壓民眾的暴亂
Now, what's most necessary to Saddam's
troops is to put down the uprising.
我們愛幹嘛就幹嘛
他們不會管我們的
We can do what we want.
They won't touch us.
好吧，但我還是會穿著
防彈衣的
All right. I'll be wearing
fashionable Kevlar.
我也是
Me too.
來吧，康拉德
Come on, Conrad.
那些碉堡到底在哪裡？
Where the hell are the bunkers?
一定就在這裡附近
Supposed to be right around here.
這些火焰很壯觀吧
How about these fires?
我已經報導過油田大火了
I already did this story, goddamn it.
要不要看看沼澤中的塘鵝？
How about a rare pelican
migration out by the marshes?
去他的塘鵝，快停車
Fuck that! Stop the car!
這附近沒有軍營
I don't see any bunkers. Do you?
我們一定會找到少校的
We'll find Major Gates, ma'am.
放屁，這裡只有鶴
Bullshit. All we're finding
is Ukrainian cranes.
它們是塘鵝
Pelicans.
這則新聞真是老掉牙了
真是浪費時間
This story has been so done.
A waste of my fucking time.
看看這些倒霉的鳥
全身沾油了油污
Look at these poor fucking birds.
簡直是生態大浩劫
All covered in some kind of fucking oil,
ecological, catastrophic....
Fuck it.
他媽的
It』s so goddamn horrible!
真可怕
Jesus Christ!
我的天啊，可憐的鳥
Poor fucking birds.
它們真可憐，慘透了
Look at them.
It』s so sad.
你別想騙我
You're not gonna fuck me.
艾奇答應要幫我找金塊
and I』m driving.
我來開車
I was promised the gold story,
按照軍方的規定，你不能開車
Military regulations. You cannot drive.
女士，麻煩你離開那輛車
Step away from the Chenowth, ma'am!
別逼我開槍
Don't make me shoot you, ma'am!
Ma'am!
求求你停車
Ma'am! Please fucking stop!
你要不要告訴我他在哪裡？
You gonna tell me where he is?
我不能告訴你
放屁
- I can't tell you. I can't.
- Bullshit!
他在哪裡？
我不能告訴你…
-Where is he?
-I can't give you that--
少來了，告訴我他在哪裡？
Come on, bitch. Tell me where he is.
我不能…
否則我就把你丟在這裡等死
- I can't, ma'am.
- You'll die here like these birds!
他在卡巴拉附近的村莊裡
It』s a village near Karbala!
好，咱們去卡巴拉吧
All right. Let's go to Karbala.
趴下…
Get down! Get down!
趴下
-Hey, get down!
-Get down!
別逼我開槍
這次我們可不是鬧著玩的
Don't make me smoke your ass, Abdul.
We're gonna have no nonsense this time.
你這個該死的騙子
Hey! You fucking liar!
Hey!
不要跑
Freeze!
根據5月3日簽的停火協議
By orders of the ceasefire
signed in Safwan, March 3rd...
美軍要扣押所有伊拉克
由科威特掠奪來的東西
...the United States military
hereby confiscates...
...all materials stolen by Iraq
from the state of Kuwait.
你們偷的東西全部要送回去
That means everything you took
is going back.
只要大家保持冷靜
我們就可以速戰速決
Everybody stay calm and
we'll get through this quickly.
懂了嗎？很好
Is that clear? Good!
去抓他
Now-- Hey! Grab that--
Hello? Hello? Hello?
契夫，別亂扣板機
Keep your finger off the trigger.
抱歉，長官
-Sorry about that, sir.
-No.
不要
可以送給你太太
For wife.
我離婚了
I』m divorced.
最新最好的產品
Newest and best. Newest and best.
這才不是最新最好的
雜音那麼大，畫面又不清不楚
Newest and best has
better noise reduction.
趴下
Less distortion. Get on the ground.
聽這種音樂不好
This is bad music. This is bad for you.
我要你告訴我黃金在哪裡
Now, I want you to tell me
where the gold is.
少校，這裡還有一扇門
There's another door over here.
沒事的，他是犯人…
It』s okay. He is prisoner. It』s okay.
對付叛黨是伊拉克的事
我們把他們帶開
不會煩你們的
Okay, okay. We take them outside
so we don't bother you, okay?
別擔心，我們待會兒
再把犯人帶回來
你最好別忘了帶他們回來
你去開那扇門
Hey. You open that door now.
去開門
Open that door.
快去
Let's go!
趴在地上
Hey. Get down on the ground.
犯人不能離開這裡
-The prisoners stay!
- You, soldier.
快趴下…
犯人不能離開
-Get on the ground!
-The prisoners must stay!
這些東西是屬於薩達姆的
薩達姆現在擔心的是叛黨
這是薩達姆的
閉嘴，他已經簽署了和平協定
Hey!
聽我說
你們從科威特搶來的東西
現在都屬於我們的了
Listen to me. Everything you stole from
Kuwait belongs to us now. You understand?
I got him.
放回去
為何？
-Put it back.
-Why?
我們要照原定計劃去找金條
而不是這些東西
We stick to the plan,
plan is for the gold. We're not thieves.
我們要找的是伊拉克的金條
We're returning Kuwaiti bullion, correct?
金條
Full.
希望萊瑟斯敞蓬車
有我想要的顏色
I』m getting a fleet of Lexus convertibles,
every color.
你這會兒可以買
萊瑟斯敞蓬車了
I told you, Lexus don't
make a convertible.
要買儘管買
但萊瑟斯沒有出敞蓬車
I'll bet you a Lexus they do.
Okay. You're on, but it won't be
a convertible. I guarantee you.
該死的
Ow. Shit! Ah.
你沒事吧？
-You all right?
- Yeah. It landed on my foot.
我的腳被金條砸到了
用這些箱子根本不能搬
They definitely didn't get it here
in these bags.
我們一定要找
別的袋子來裝才行
The tensilary strength in these
is only 200 pounds.
什麼？
-What?
- Tensilary strength.
我要找別的袋子來裝
他以前在機場工作
He works at an airport.
這種袋子可以裝
65磅左右的東西
If we put it in one
of these Vuitton bags...
...they can hold about 65 pounds,
maybe more.
還有沒有別的行李箱？
You have any more luggage?
這裡歸美國軍方管
United States military
is in charge here.
我在加油站看到一輛卡車
I saw a truck out by the gas station.
什麼加油站？
上面那個加油站
-What gas station?
-The one upstairs.
我上去看看
Let's see what U-Haul has on the lot.
我們需要一輛卡車
Conrad. We need a truck.
你們找到了嗎？
Did we get it? Did we get it?
找到了嗎？
找到了
很多嗎？
-We got it.
-Is it a lot?
多的不得了
你們上面沒事吧？
Conrad, you have no idea.
Are you cool here?
他們根本不理我
Yeah. They've been ignoring me.
你保持冷靜就好了
我去找一輛卡車
Don't worry about it. Just stay calm.
I』m gonna find a truck.
快離開那輛卡車
Move! Move away from the vehicle!
快走
Let's go!
你們要帶走科威特的黃金？
You take the Kuwaiti gold, yes?
是的
We take the Kuwaiti gold, yes.
不能讓薩達姆留下來？
不能
- Saddam cannot keep?
- No, Saddam cannot keep.
薩達姆現在要煩心的事
實在在太多了
Saddam have too many problem today.
沒錯
要我們幫忙拿嗎？
-He certainly does.
-You need help to carry?
那就麻煩你們了
I think we'll be all right.
這兩個人會去幫你們
對，他們會幫你們
-These men help you.
-Yeah, these men help you.
你們趕快拿完東西走人吧
And then you go away fast
from all this bullshit.
繼續搬…
Keep it going, keep it going.
不要走，求求你們不要走
Don't leave. Please don't leave.
不要走
Don't leave!
救救我們，不要走
Look!
救救我們
Help!
Look! Look!
求求你們
Please!
不要走…
Don't go. Don't go.
請你們走吧
You go now, please.
我看沒這麼簡單
I don't think so.
這個男人意圖叛亂
This man is leader of uprising.
少校，按照原定計劃進行吧
Major, let's just stick to the plan.
The plan is for the gold.
我們可以先幫他們然後再離開
We can help these people first,
then we'll be on our way.
不行，我們是來找黃金的
走吧
This is not what we're here for.
Let's go!
各位…
Cover me.
不要隨便開槍，康拉德
你知道會有什麼後果
No unnecessary shots, Conrad,
because we know what they do.
會害人被膽汁感染得到敗血症
They make infected pockets
full of bile, sir.
沒錯
That's right, that's what they do.
我要你們離開這裡
I want you to leave this town.
我們離開的話會被薩達姆殺死的
連我們的家人都不會放過
Saddam kill us if we leave.
Kill our family.
我們已經讓你們拿黃金走了
現在你就不能來煩我們了
We give you the gold.
Now U.S.A. out of Iraq.
不要開槍
No shooting.
好，我們好好談談
Okay. Okay, we work something out.
不要激動…
Easy! Take it easy!
怎麼了？
What's happening?
不過是小意外罷了，別緊張
Accident. Stay cool.
不
No!
雙手舉高
Put your hands up.
特洛
Troy!
Troy?
我沒事
I』m okay.
趴下
-Chief.
-Get down.
趴下…
Shut up! Get down!
Get down! Shut up.
帶這些人上吉普車
-Put the people in the Humvee.
- What?
什麼？
帶這些人上吉普車
Put the people in the Humvee.
坐不下的
那就想想辦法
-There's no room.
- Make room.
你說的「需要」怎麼了？
What happened to necessity?
情況改變了
It just changed!
我不這麼認為，走吧
Not for me. Let's go!
如果剛剛的事
發生在你身上怎麼辦？
如果是你呢？
-What if that was you?
-What if this was you without Kevlar?
Hey! Hey.
好極了，還有坦克車
Great, a fucking tank.
我們這會兒慘了
That should send us on our way.
要開火嗎，長官？
L.A.W., sir?
不，咱們離開這裡吧
No, let's get out of here.
早該走了
It』s about fucking time!
快上車吧
Ride in that Humvee. Let's go!
Let's go! In the Humvee.
快…
Come on, sweetheart.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
你瘋啦，薩達姆會殺你的
你這個大笨蛋
我們本來已經沒事了
Stupid son of a bitch.
We were home free!
讓我看看你的手
Give me that arm.
那架坦克在做什麼？
What's that tank doing?
我不知道，好像停了
I don't know. Looks like it stopped.
他讓他們把黃金和犯人帶走
他們破壞了停火協定
快想想辦法
Mortar!
是毒氣彈
It』s gas!
我的防毒面罩呢？
Where's my mask?
Where's my fucking mask?
我的防毒面罩呢？
Where's my mask?
特洛
Mine!
不要跑…
Hey, stop! Stop!
等等，有地雷
Hey! Wait! Those are mines!
快回來
Come back this way!
不要跑
Hey, stop!
這不是沙林毒氣
否則我們早就死了
No, no, no, this isn't sarin.
We'd be dead already.
那這是什麼，摧淚瓦斯嗎？
- It』s C.S. Come on.
對，來吧
- What is it, mustard?
沒錯，他們抓走拜隆了
- Tear gas?
- Yeah, times 10.
過來，把這戴上
Come here. Come here. Put this on.
你拿去戴吧
Here, you take it.
這裡有地雷，不要走那邊
You see that? That's a mine!
Come here.
遮住你的臉
Don't step there. Do not step there.
Where's your kids?
過來，你的孩子呢？
Cover your face. Come here.
Where are your children?
你的孩子怎麼了？
What happened to your children?
小心後面
Watch your back!
不要動
Freeze! Don't move!
怎麼回事？
我不知道
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
不要緊的，他們是來幫我們的
他們是反抗軍
It』s okay. They're helping us.
They're with the rebels.
他們附近有地方可以躲
They got a shelter.
Tunnel.
快進去
Go, go. Get in!
我去找拜隆
I gotta look for Barlow.
特洛呢？
Where's Troy?
Wait a minute! Where's Troy?
我們快點離開這裡
Hey, man. We gotta get out of here.
特洛呢？
快來
Where is Troy?
別碰我
- Come on!
- Get off me!
我們進去吧
Let's go.
You motherfucker.
Get the fuck off me!
拜隆
Barlow?
你們在搞什麼鬼？
Get the fuck off me.
我們要去找特洛
We have to go back and get Troy.
他不在上面
等摧淚瓦斯散了再說
He's not out there.
We have to wait till it clears.
都是你害我們損失了特洛
You made a choice in the village
and we lost Troy.
我沒有選擇
才怪
我別無選擇
-I had no choice.
-You had a choice!
I had no choice.
那特洛呢？
他現在有什麼選擇？
What about Troy?
What choice does he have now?
我們能打死他嗎？
我們不該扣留美國人
他們破壞了停火協定
叛軍在搶坦克
快點開始拍
Paco, start shooting!
我覺得情況不妙
我們最好趕快離開
I don't like this. We should go.
讓我來處理
Let me handle this.
快穿衣服
知道了
-Get dressed! Get dressed!
- Okay.
快穿衣服
我說我知道了
I said okay!
Fuck!
你會說英文嗎？
會
-Do you speak English?
-Yes.
我遇上麻煩了，我要…
-Could you--?
-Yes, sir?
I have a little problem.
請問你要接幾號？
I need to know the number.
What number, please?
「沙漠風暴」行動
Operation Desert Storm.
對不起，你說什麼？
I』m sorry? I need to know the number.
幫我接沙漠中的指揮中心
這是緊急事件
The big Army in the desert.
It』s an emergency.
你必須要告訴我號碼才行
你去死
-You'll have to give me more specific--
-Fuck. Maybe--
快點…
Come on, come on, come on.
喂？
Hello.
-Honey, it's me.
親愛的，是我
Troy? Aah!
特洛？我的天啊
我正希望你會打來呢
Oh, my God! Oh, baby,
I was hoping it was you.
是我，親愛的
-It』s me, honey.
寶寶哭了
-Oh, God, the baby's crying.
她還好嗎？
How's she doing?
她睡的不太安穩
go back to work, so I』m real tired, baby.
我媽回去上班了
所以我現在很累
She hasn't slept good, and Mom had to
我真希望我能幫得上忙，寶貝
你何時回來？
-I wish I was there to help, gooney bird.
-When are you coming home?
我正在設法，親愛的
Well, I』m working on that right now.
我看到報上有電腦公司在徵人
要不要幫你安排面試？
I saw an ad for a computer job.
You want me to set up an interview?
聽著，親愛的…
你什麼時候回來？
-Listen, honey--
-What date are you coming home?
他們還沒有告訴我們
確切的日期
They haven't given us
an exact date yet--
如果我知道你哪天會回來
我可以幫你安排…
If I knew,
I could set up this interview--
親愛的，求求你聽我說
怎麼了？
-Listen to me, please.
-What's happening?
那是什麼？
牆壁爆炸了
-What was that?
-The wall just exploded.
戰爭不是結束了嗎？
I thought the war was over.
還沒有，幫我個忙
打電話給後備軍人指揮中心
It is and it isn't.
Could you call the reserve center?
你要我怎麼做？
What do you want me to do?
告訴他們，我被困在
卡拉巴北方223的碉堡中
Tell the duty NCO I』m stuck in a bunker
near 223 north outside Karbala.
卡拉巴北方223
Two-two-three north outside Karbala.
你沒事吧？
別擔心我
-You're okay? Everything's okay?
-I don't want you to worry.
我正在想辦法為我們家籌些錢
I tried to do something
for the family, and....
我只想告訴你…
告訴我什麼？
-I just want you to know--
-Know what?
我愛你
告訴我到底怎麼了？
-I love you.
-What's going on?
告訴克莉絲，我也愛她
-Just tell Krystal.
-Troy.
告訴克莉絲，我們發財了
Tell Krystal I』m a rich man and if things
如果一切順利
她就不愁吃穿了
work out, she'll be taken care of.
我得掛了，親愛的，我愛你
What are you talking about?
-I gotta go, gooney bird! I love you!
-What's going on?
Troy? Troy?
軍營中一片歡欣鼓舞
Spirits are high
and the music is soaring...
年輕的士兵們，正在慶祝成功解放科威特
...as these young troops
celebrate the liberation of Kuwait.
我現在被困在一個…
該死的，等等
The mood here is boisterous and giddy,
as these troops are--
I』m being held by a bunker outside--
Shit! Wait!
我現在被伊拉克人
扣押在佈滿砂礫的卡拉巴…
I』m being held captive by Iraqi troops
outside a bunker near the gritty city--
等等…你又說了砂礫
Cut, cut! You said "gritty city" again.
誰管我說了什麼
這些人就要死了
Who gives a shit what I said?
These people are dying, for chrissake!
華特怎辦？
-What about Private Wogaman, Adriana?
- Let's lay one down first.
我們先報新聞再說，3，2…
I』m being held captive by Iraqi troops....
In three, two....
我被伊拉克軍隊扣押在卡拉巴軍營
Okay. Okay. Okay.
反抗軍已經…
The rebels have gone down the road....
那是NBS的記者
Okay.
她本人看起來矮多了
快把她帶開
這次攻擊行動，顯然是由卡拉巴叛軍發動的
Now, the assault, started by
the rebels from Karbala, came up on--
退後
別鬧了
Hey, back off! Hey, hey! No!
我們有權到這裡來
Sir, that's enough!
-We have a right to be here!
那是我的
去死吧
That's mine.
華特
-Yes.
- No.
麻煩把褲子還給我，好嗎？
Yes. Fuck it. Walter?
我要我的褲子
-Could I have my pants, please?
- Walter?
快走
華特…
- My pants, on my legs.
- Go!
快走
Walter?
快離開這裡
- Go!
- Out! Get out!
你小時候希望以後能當什麼？
What did you wanna be as a little boy?
我小時候想當獸醫或神槍手
As a boy, I wanted to be either
a veterinarian or a CIA sharpshooter.
真的？真複雜
-Really? That's very complicated.
- Doug?
道格
什麼事？
Yes, colonel.
你在搞什麼鬼？
我在接受NRG的訪問
-What the fuck are you doing?
- I』m giving an interview to NRG.
你有沒有得到批准？
有的
-Do you have authorization?
-Yes, sir, I do.
不行
不行？
No.
-No?
-No.
這是誰給你的？
蓋特少校
-Who gave you this?
-Major Gates.
這是艾奇蓋特給你的？
我的天啊，道格
Archie Gates gave you this?
Jesus Christ, Doug.
我不能接受訪問嗎？
不行
-I don't get to do the interview?
-No, you don't get to do the interview.
跟我來
Come with me.
你告訴我他在哪裡
否則我送你回旅館
Tell me where he is, or you're going
back to the hotel in Dhahran.
我不知道他在哪裡
他不是去了幫愛德安娜嗎？
I don't know. I think
he's helping Adriana Cruz.
她在不在這裡？
不在
-Is she here?
- No, sir.
還有誰不見了？
So who else is missing?
契夫不見了
契夫不見了？
-Chief's not here.
- Chief's not here?
你不知道你的部下在哪裡嗎？
You don't know where
your staff sergeant is, captain?
拜隆和維克也不見了
Barlow and Vig are gone too, sir.
他們昨天在某個傢伙的屁股裡
找到一張文件
They got a document
out of a guy's ass yesterday, sir.
什麼？
What?
我不知道那是什麼
好像是地圖或是秘密名冊
我親眼看到的
I don't know what it was. Some map
or secret list. But I saw it happen.
他們有沒有拿來給你看？
沒有
-Did they bring it to you?
-No, sir.
我就知道他在搞鬼
Yeah, see, he's working something.
幫我找些地圖來
Get me some maps.
Check radio transmissions.
檢查一下無線電通訊
也許能找出他們的位置
Maybe we'll get their positions.
他怎麼了？他死了嗎？
What's wrong with him? Is he dead?
他死了嗎？
你們要帶他到哪裡去？
Is that guy dead?
Where are you gonna put him?
我們帶他到神廟去
A shrine.
神廟？你們這裡有什麼樣的神廟？
A shrine? What kind of shrine y'all got?
聖人的神廟，能夠撫慰他
並帶他到天堂去
A shrine near a holy man...
...that gives him comfort
and access to paradise.
這個神廟聽起來蠻不錯
對不對？
Hey, that sounds like
a pretty good shrine, right, chief?
我說真的，聽起來真的很好
I』m not kidding.
It sounds like a good shrine.
很抱歉，我不該打你
我只是很擔心特洛
Hey, man, I』m sorry I hit you.
他是我朋友，我不希望他出事
I was just worried about Troy,
you know. He's my friend.
I didn't want nothing
to happen to him.
他說要帶我到底特律去，幫我找工作
He's gonna take me to Detroit
with him, hook me up with a job.
別生氣了嘛
Come on, man. Chief.
我知道你是來幫我的
I know you was coming to help me.
我不希望，我們兩人之間有任何不快
Thanks. I don't wanna hold no grudges.
你是不是喪失了自己的信仰？
You got kicked out of that
ring of Jesus fire, huh?
不是這樣的
That ain't how it work.
那是怎樣？
How's it work?
不管他讓我面臨任何困境，我都坦然處之
完全沒有任何疑問
I take care of whatever he puts
in front of me, no questions asked.
他讓我找到了黃金
所以我就拿了
He put that gold in front of me,
and I took it.
就是這樣
That's how it works.
那現在呢？
What about now?
我不知道，靜觀其變吧
I don't know. I gotta see.
你還好嗎，康拉德？
-I』m fine.
我沒事
-How you doing, Conrad?
今天的事是我造成的
It was my choice today.
你可以回去拿你的黃金
把它埋了
You can try and head back if you want.
Take your share and bury it.
我自己去找拜隆
I'll find Barlow myself.
我也要去找特洛
I wanna find Troy.
我隨時準備出發
I』m here. I』m ready.
我們先看看皮箱裡的東西吧
Let's check the suitcases.
一共有79個
I count 79.
這表示少了41袋
That means we're missing 41 bags.
這樣一共有2300百萬
收穫還不錯
That's about $23 million left.
不過我們當然要找到拜隆
而且不受到軍法審判才行
Not bad for a disaster, provided we find
Barlow and not get court-martialed.
她還好吧？
How is she?
你女兒還好吧？
Hey. How is your little girl?
她嚇壞了
She's traumatized.
What do you expect?
我在美國念過商學院
I went to B-school
at Bowling Green, okay?
我回來是想在這裡開飯店
I came back to open
a couple of hotels near Karbala.
在這場愚笨的戰爭開始之前
我幾乎要轉虧為盈了
I』m nearly in the black
when this stupid war starts...
你們卻來炸了我的餐廳
...and you guys bomb all my cafes.
現在我們想要反抗薩達姆
布希卻棄我們於不顧
Now we try to get rid of Saddam...
...Bush leaves us twisting in the winds.
Unbelievable.
看看這些人
美國為何不伸出援手？
Look at these people.
Where is America now?
美軍為何不來幫我們？
Where is the Army now?
你們有無線電嗎？
-Do you have a radio?
- No.
沒有無線電，也沒有水
No radio, no water.
拜隆呢？
他被他們抓走了
-Where's Barlow?
- They got him.
他們會帶他到哪裡去？
綠洲碉堡
Where would they take him?
那裡的戒備森嚴
Oasis bunker.
It』s full of Saddam's Republican Guard.
碉堡在什麼地方？
離這裡18英哩左右
Where's that?
-Approximately 17, 18 miles from here.
帶我們去
我們沒有交通工具
Take us there.
-We have no transportation.
那就用走的
直到找到車輛為止
你們為何不聯絡海軍？
We'll walk till we find some.
-Why don't you call in the Marines?
怎麼聯絡？我們又沒有無線電
-With what? We don't have a radio.
- Okay.
我們幫你找輛車
你開回軍營去找架直升機
幫我們找幫手來
We'll find a vehicle, you drive back,
get a helicopter, fly in, get your man.
礙難從命
為何？你們有大軍駐紮
We can't do that.
-Why not? You have a huge Army here.
我們不該捲入你們的內政
We shouldn't be involved
in the uprising.
我們打死了伊拉克士兵
已經違反了停火協議
We killed Iraqi soldiers,
broke the peace accord.
你知道我是怎麼想的嗎？
你們在偷黃金
You know what I think?
我們為了反抗薩達姆，傷亡慘重
你們卻在偷黃金
You're stealing gold. We're fighting Saddam
and dying, and you're stealing gold.
你錯了
You're wrong.
有50萬美軍駐紮在此
卻只派了你們4個來拿黃金？
They have half a million men here.
They send four guys
to pick up all this bullion?
我看不是吧
I don't think so.
我們一定要找到我們的人
你要多少黃金
才肯幫我們的忙？
We need to find our man.
How much do you want to take us to him?
你有什麼資格分配黃金？
Is this still yours to give? Huh?
你們能拿到黃金
是因為有我們幫忙
The only reason you have these bags
is my people picked them up.
我們會拿屬於我們的份
幫你們搬運你們的
We'll take our share...
...and we will help you
carry your share.
還要幫我們找到我們的弟兄
And find our man.
我叫做艾米爾阿布杜拉
Amir Abdulah.
我是艾奇蓋特
Archie Gates.
你們要帶我們到伊朗邊境
什麼？
-You'll take us to the Iranian border.
-What?
要是我們不趕快到難民營的話
就死定了
最近的難民營在伊朗境內
If we don't get to a refugee camp,
we are dead. The nearest is in Iran.
你不需要我們
你們可以買通一條出路
You don't need us. Buy your way.
薩達姆的士兵不會拿這些黃金
No. Saddam's soldiers
will never take Saddam's gold.
我們只有跟著美國人，才有活命的希望
Our only chance
is if we are with Americans.
我們不能帶你們到伊朗邊境
那我們也不能幫你們的忙
-We can't take you to the Iranian border.
-Then we don't have a deal.
少來這套
我們救了你們一命
-Give me a fucking break, man.
-We just saved your life!
我們也救了你們
我們為了你們損失了一名弟兄
-And we saved yours.
-We lost a man for you.
把我們丟在這裡任人宰割
對你們有什麼好處
What good is it if you leave us here
to be slaughtered, huh?
民主大軍打敗了醜陋的獨栽者
解救了富有的科威特人
The big Army of democracy beats the ugly
dictator and saves the rich Kuwaitis...
而你們會因為幫助我們
逃離獨栽者的魔掌而坐牢嗎？
...but you go to jail if you help us
escape the same dictator?
你們也看到我太太的下場
You saw what happened to my wife.
看看我的女兒
Look at my daughter.
多少人要去？
Who's going?
除了神父外，大家都去
一共55個人
Everyone but the priests. That makes 55.
我們有從吉普車上搶救什麼下來嗎？
Did we save anything from the Humvee?
有，維克的包包
Yeah. Vig's bag.
好極了
Lovely.
你是什麼軍階？
What is your rank, bro?
一等兵
Sergeant first class.
哪個連？
Your company?
美國後備軍人437連
437 Civil Affairs Company,
U.S. Army Reserve.
好朋友，告訴我一件事
My main man...
...tell me something, okay?
麥可傑克森到底是怎麼回事？
What is the problem
with Michael Jackson?
你這話什麼意思？
What do you mean?
麥可傑克森到底是怎麼回事？
What is the problem
with Michael Jackson?
你不懂我的問題嗎？
You understand my question?
我不太懂
No, I』m not sure I do.
流行樂之王
The King of Pop. Woo-hoo. Hee, hee.
麥可傑克森
Yeah, Michael Jackson.
他到埃及來了
我在報上看到他的照片
He come to Egypt.
I see picture in newspaper.
他帶著白手套跟大家打招呼
"I』m Michael Jackson in my hotel room...
「我是一天到晚整容的麥可傑克森」
"Hello," with the white glove.
你們國家逼他去整容
...with my chop-up face."
Your country make him chop up his face.
應該不是這樣吧
I don't think so.
麥可傑克森是你們這個變態國家的流行樂之王
Michael Jackson is pop king
of sick fucking country.
放屁，他是自願的
That's bullshit. He did it to himself.
我看在放屁的人是你
You are the blind bullshit, my main man.
這事再明顯不過了
It is so obvious a black man...
黑人漂白皮膚，洗直頭髮
你知道為何嗎？
...make the skin white and the hair
straight, and you know why?
不知道
No.
你們這個變態國家，逼得黑人自我嫌惡
Your sick fucking country
make the black man hate himself...
就像你們恨這裡被你們
轟炸的阿拉伯人和孩子們一樣
...just like you hate the Arab
and the children you bomb over here.
我不恨小孩
I don't hate children.
大戰已經結束了
你這樣做不合法
所以你也已經犯法了
-This is illegal. The war's over.
-That's why you are illegal.
你們破壞停火協議，而且還偷了黃金
You broke the ceasefire,
and I think maybe even you steal the gold.
所以沒有人知道
你們現在在這裡
So nobody know where you are, right?
Your Army don't know.
我可以把你送到巴格達去
永遠不會有人找到你
I』m gonna send you to Baghdad
for a long time. Nobody found you.
他們關心嗎？
誰？
-Do they care, buddy?
-Does who care?
美軍關心伊拉克的孩子嗎？
他們有回來幫忙嗎？
Do your Army care about the children
in Iraq? Do they come back to help?
不，他們不會來的
No, they're not coming.
你的軍隊是不是回來
幫助反抗軍？
Do your Army...
不會
-...come back to help the people?
- No.
說實話吧
Tell the truth, dude-ski.
免得吃苦頭
Save us the big bummer.
我說的都是實話
That's the truth.
會不會痛？
Does it hurt?
我剛問你會不會痛？
I asked you a question, man.
Does it hurt?
很痛
Yes, it hurts.
你們轟炸了我的家人
你知道嗎？
You bomb my family. Do you know that?
你們夷平了我住的那條街
You blow up my home. The whole street.
我太太被大塊水泥
砸的血肉模糊
My wife is crushed by
big fucking block of concrete.
她失去了雙腿
She lose her legs.
她的雙腿已經被切除了
Those legs cut off now.
真是太可怕了
什麼？
That's horrible.
-What?
我說那太可怕了
I said that's horrible.
我還沒說到可怕的部份呢
Oh, my God, buddy. I didn't even
told you the horrible part yet.
我兒子在床上被活活炸死
My son....
My son was killed in his bed.
他才一歲大
He is 1 years old.
抱著玩具睡覺時卻被炸死了
He is sleeping with his toy
when the bomb come.
我有個女兒
I have a daughter.
你真好命
Very nice for you, bro.
她安全的住在亞歷桑那
She's safe in Arizona...
不用擔心從天而降的
炸彈和水泥塊
...without the bomb, the concrete
and all this shit.
我不是亞歷桑那人
I』m not from Arizona.
她多大了？
How old is she?
一個月大
One month old.
她叫什麼名字？
What's her name?
克莉絲
Krystal.
你為何要告訴我這些？
What make you decide to tell me
about Krystal, my main man?
因為我們兩個都為人父
Because we're both fathers.
我已經不是父親了，記得嗎？
我兒子已經死了
I』m not father no more, dude.
Remember?
My son is dead now.
如果我去轟炸你的女兒
你會有何感覺？
Can you think how it feel
inside your heart...
...if I bomb your daughter?
我會覺得痛不欲生
Worse than death.
你說的對
痛不欲生
That's right. Worse than death.
你們都認為美國很邪惡
對不對？
你們認為美國是撒旦？
Y'all think America is Satan, right?
America is Satan?
他們說什麼？
What'd they say?
他們說希望能開一家理髮廳
They say he want salon.
什麼？
理髮廳
-A what?
-A salon. Hair salon.
你會剪頭髮？
You cut hair?
對
-Yes.
-Yes, yes.
他們才不管自己的客戶
是美國人，什葉派教徒
還是回教徒
Look, they don't care if they cut
American hair, Shiite hair, Sunni hair.
他們只想逃離海珊的暴政
然後過著平靜的生活
They just want get rid of Saddam
and live life. Make business.
他想知道你們是不是要殺光
所有的阿拉伯人
He wants to know,
do you want to kill every Arab?
我們受訓的時候是這樣學的
That's what I was trained to do.
不，不是這樣的
我們也有阿拉伯盟國
No. That was not our training.
We got Arab allies, man.
沒錯，我們有阿拉伯盟國
Yeah, well, we got Arab allies.
他說「所以你們不想
殺光阿拉人羅？」
He says, "So you don't want to
kill every Arab."
他沒有念過高中
-Well, not--
-He's just had no high school.
別到處宣揚
-No high school.
-Don't tell people that.
他們說什麼？
說你的髮型糟透了
-What'd they say?
-He says you have terrible haircut.
這是特洛幫我剪的，很酷呢
Troy gave me this haircut.
It』s a badass haircut.
Yeah!
美國萬歲
America!
-America!
歡迎美國人
America, welcome.
Welcome, America! Welcome!
Major Gates.
你好
他在問候你們
-How you doing?
-He says, "How are you?"
他很高興有美國人來
He's happy to welcome America.
謝謝
我們歡迎美國人
-Thank you.
-We welcome America.
他們都是海珊的逃兵
They're all deserters.
They leave Saddam army.
但他們常常幫助我們
他是個大好人
-But they help us near Karbala. Good man.
-Karbala.
Welcome, America.
不，男人不這樣叫
只有女人會叫
No, no, my friend. The man don't do that.
Only the woman.
為何？
這是他們的習俗
-Why's that?
-Because it's their custom.
你們有沒有無線電？
沒有
-You have a radio?
- No radio.
布希一定要現在就解決海珊
George Bush get rid Saddams now?
不盡然
恭喜你
-Not exactly, no.
-Congratulation!
恭喜你
Congratulation!
麻煩你告訴他
我們需要交通工具
Would you inform this gentleman
we need a vehicle of some kind?
從科威特搶來的
From Kuwait.
我問你一個問題
Man, let me ask you a question.
萊瑟斯有沒有這款車？
Does Lexus make this model?
只有永恆有敞蓬
Infiniti convertible only.
沒有萊瑟斯敞蓬車
只有永恆的
No Lexus convertible. Infiniti only.
只有永恆有
Infiniti only.
我就知道
Exactly what I said.
我們要用這些車
來對抗海珊的軍隊
Listen. We use these cars
to fight Saddam's soldiers.
有什麼好笑？
What's so funny?
不能給你們
Cannot take.
你這話什麼意思？
我們打敗了海珊
我們當然可以拿
What you mean, cannot take?
We kicked Saddam's ass. We definitely take.
我們是美國軍人
We are the United States Army.
你們是三個帶著一群百姓的人
而且沒有吉普車
You are three guys with a bunch
of civilians and no Humvee.
我們沒有錢過日子
Need money. Have no money.
To eat, to live.
美軍陣容龐大，有飛機，坦克
我們什麼都沒有
"American Army is huge. It has planes
and tanks, and we have nothing."
聽我說，我們會一起起義反抗
告訴他
Listen to me.
We will rise up together. Tell him.
起義
Rise up.
你看看我們有許多種族
來自許多國家
Look at us. Many races.
我們一起同心協力
Many nations, many nations.
Working together.
告訴他，契夫
-Tell him, chief.
-Yes. We're united.
我們很團結
團結一致
United.
喬治布希需要你們
George Bush. George Bush wants you.
You. You.
你們要為自己挺身反抗
Stand up for yourself.
喬治布希需要你們
他需要你，他需要大家
-George Bush?
- Wants you!
- You!
- Wants you.
-You!
- Yes!
我們要團結起來挺身反抗
-He wants everybody.
-Yes. Me and you stand up together.
我們要一起打敗海珊
We fight. Kick Saddam's ass!
Huh?
喬治布希需要你們
-George Bush wants you.
-Yes.
He wants you.
你們要為自己的自由而戰
要自助才會人助
He wants you!
Make the fight for freedom on your own!
讚美上帝
-Then America will follow.
- Praise the Lord!
天祐美國，天祐自由伊拉克
God bless America,
and God bless a free Iraq!
自由伊拉克
Free Iraq! Free Iraq!
- Free Iraq! Free Iraq!
- Free Iraq!
Free Iraq!
怎麼樣？
Now, what do you say, my friend?
不能給你車
Cannot give car. Ha, ha.
那我們就用買的
Okay. I guess we'll buy them.
別這樣，這音樂很好聽的
聽了讓你精神百倍
Come on, man. This is good music.
Man, Judas Priest will pump you up, man.
我才不要聽這種音樂
會讓我頭痛
No! We're not listening to that
headache music. Stop.
聽一首就好了嘛
我們應該聽輕音樂
-Just one song.
-What you need is easy-listening classics.
我才不要聽
I do not need that.
你需要聽音樂放鬆一下
聽這種音樂才不能放鬆
-You need something to calm your nerve.
-Not easy-listening classics.
聽這張
All right, try this.
這是巴洛的太太
從底特律傳來的
這應該就是他的下落
Sir, this is from Barlow's wife in Detroit.
They may have a position on him.
他太太從底特律傳來的？
From his wife in Detroit?
這到底是怎麼回事？
What the hell is this?
戰爭結束了，我卻不知道
這場戰爭到底有何意義？
The war is over, and I don't fucking know
what it was about. What was this war about?
我被軍方耍著玩
我也是
-I was managed by the military.
-Me too.
我報新聞不是靠個人風格取勝
而是靠內容
I try to be substance-based,
not style-based.
我覺得你很有格
I think you got a lot of style.
那個叫凱西的小婊子說我老了
That little Cathy bitch says I』m old.
那是因為她嫉妒
That's because she's jealous.
你比她聰明讓她備受威脅
第二，你很漂亮
First of all, you are smarter than her,
and that is a threat.
你是電視台最美麗的女人
謝謝
And second of all, you are beautiful.
You're the most prettiest woman...
-...down there at that network.
-Thank you.
你皮膚很好，一頭秀髮
You got great skin, beautiful hair.
你真會說話
但幹我們這一行的
就是政治角力
That's sweet, but there's
sexual politics in this business.
最重要的三件事
就是外表，性和風格
It』s about looks, it's about sex,
it's about style.
很多主播都找過我
但我不為所動
Many an anchormen came on to me.
I didn't go for it.
我不需要
我從來不為五斗米出賣色相
I never played that game, never dropped
to my knees for an assignment.
我之所以到這裡來
是因為別人沒種來
Christ, I came out to the desert because
nobody else had the fucking balls to do it.
我從軍是為了想改善
家人的生活，買棟好房子
I only joined Saddam Hussein army
to make good living for my family.
Good house.
但現在卻無法脫身
Now I can't get out.
我也是為了賺錢才從軍
I joined up for the extra cash too.
我發現我太太懷孕了
Found out I was gonna have a baby.
是美國人教我怎麼用武器的
You know, I got
weapon and training from America.
騙人
Bullshit.
你以為我的英文是怎麼學的？
Oh, yeah?
How you think I learned my English?
兩伊戰爭時
美國人來教我們如何對抗伊朗
Specialist guys come here...
...to train us when we fight Iran.
他們教了你們什麼？
What'd they train you in?
武器，秘密破壞行動，審問
Weapons, sabotage...
...interrogation.
好極了
Great.
你們到伊拉克來打仗
一點意義都沒有
It was a total waste for your Army
to come to Iraq, right?
我聽說科威特
發生了不幸的事情
I heard about a lot of bad shit
that happened in Kuwait.
這種事情難免發生
我也覺得很丟臉
Yeah, bad shit happened.
I』m not proud of that.
到底哪一個國家才變態？
Who's got the sick country?
也許海珊瘋了
Maybe Saddam is very crazy.
你們也瘋了才會轟炸伊拉克
And then you are crazy
to bomb all of Iraq.
大肆轟炸的確瘋狂
但解救科威特卻很理智
Too much bombing is crazy,
but not saving Kuwait.
你們是來救科威特人的？
是的
You are here for save Kuwaiti people?
-Yes.
真的？
是的
-Really?
-Yeah.
世界上有麻煩的人太多了
你們為何不幫他們出頭？
A lot of people
in trouble in this world, my man...
...and you don't fight
no fucking war for them.
你們入侵了別的國家
這是不可以的
為何不能？
-You invaded another country. Can't do that.
-Why not, dude?
這樣會使世界一片混亂
我們一定要維持局勢安定
It makes the world crazy.
You need to keep it stable.
為何？
為了石油嗎？
For what? Your pickup truck?
不，是為了維持
這個區域的安定
No, for stability. Stabilize the region.
這才是你要的安定
This is your fucking stability,
my main man.
我們先去救我們的人
然後回來拿黃金
We get our man, and then we
come back and pick up the gold.
還要接我們嗎？
沒錯
-And my people?
-That's right.
讓我們再沙盤推演一次
Let's go over the plan.
好
Let's do it.
懸崖上有一個碉堡
看起來像是一座城堡
There's a bunker built into
the side of the cliff face.
這裡有兩條路
It looks like a castle. There's a road
coming there, another one across.
路上全是海珊的人馬
我不認為能夠壓制他們
It』s full of Saddam's Republican Guard.
Now, I don't think we can overpower them.
太多人了
There's too many.
不過他們只怕一件事
什麼事？
-But there's one thing they're afraid of.
-What's that?
海珊
Saddam.
我們正好可以利用這點
Then that's what we use.
好，就這麼辦
Right. That's what we'll use.
保佑我，請你保佑我
You stay with me.
等等，我想再詳細的
討論一下這個計劃
Wait, hold on a minute. I wanna
go over this plan one more time.
你很害怕，對吧？
You're scared, right?
也許吧
Maybe.
是這樣的，你要想辦法
做好這件讓你害怕的事
The way this works is, you do
the thing you're scared shitless of...
事後再鼓起勇氣
...and you get the courage after
you do it. Not before you do it.
這樣太笨了吧
應該是反過來才對
That's a dumb-ass way to work.
It should be the other way around.
我知道
I know.
就是這樣
That's the way it works.
海珊來了
你們讓他失望，他很火大
他要把你們全殺光
我的天啊
他鬼扯
他來了
海珊來殺我們了
If you leave me now
You'll take away the biggest part of me
No, baby, please don't go
You'll take away the very heart of me
怎麼了？
手被刺傷了
Ow! I got a splinter.
你們不是海珊的人
How could we let it slip away?
該死的
別跑，等等
Jesus fire, Jesus fire, Jesus fire....
上帝啊…
來吧
Come on.
快點
Quickly, quickly.
該死的
Oh, shit.
你沒事吧？
You all right?
天啊，你死了
Oh, shit, you're dead.
你們這些懦夫
快點回去打他們
我們有直升機，我們會贏的
等等…
Wait! Wait!
該死的
Shit.
快回來
Get back. Get back inside.
艾米爾，快點
Come on. Amir, come on.
- Huh? How you feel?
- Stop!
I told you....
我們走吧
Let's get out of here.
康拉德呢？
Where's Conrad?
大家不要放鬆警戒
Keep your guard up.
你沒事吧？
Barlow, are you okay?
康拉德呢？
我們要怎麼回去？
Chief. Where's Conrad?
How we getting back, man?
我們有一輛勞斯萊斯
-We got the Rolls.
- You got a Rolls?
你們有勞斯萊斯？
對
-Yeah.
-Hey. Hey.
這是一輛永恆敞蓬車
This is an Infiniti convertible.
你不是被嚇呆了嗎？
Man, I think you're in shock.
這是一輛永恆敞蓬車
對不對？
-It』s an Infiniti convertible, isn't it?
對
- Yeah, it is.
就算我欠你一輛車
我可沒被嚇呆
Okay, so I owe you a car.
I』m not in shock.
你沒事吧
You sure you're okay?
不要動
Hey, freeze!
不，他是跟我們一道兒的
No! He's with us!
別開槍，他是我們的人
Don't shoot him. He's with us!
你是那個帶著小女孩的人？
沒錯
You're the guy with the little girl?
-That's right.
你在這裡做什麼？
What are you doing here?
是他幫我們找到你的
我是來救你的
He helped us find you.
-I came here to help you.
你真是個大好人
All right. You're all right, man.
我看到有人
但看不出在幹嘛，你不要動
I see some people.
I can't see what's happening. Stay put.
你女兒好嗎？
她暫時沒事
-How's your little girl?
-She's safe for now.
好極了，我們能怎麼幫你們？
Outstanding, excellent.
How can we help you?
你們說好要送我們到邊境去
不過現在人數增加了
我們需要更多車子
We had a deal to get to the border, but now
we have more people and need vehicles.
沒問題，我們會想辦法的
That's not a problem.
We'll work it out.
我們一定要救他們，沒問題的
We have to do this.
We can work it out, okay?
他們人很多耶
I don't know. It』s a lot of people.
那你去告訴他們
我們只能帶一些人
Okay, well, then you choose who we take.
Tell the others they're gonna have to die...
其他人就只有在這裡等死
你去說，我說不出口
...because I can't do that.
-You're gonna have to do it yourself.
- Okay, okay.
Okay.
你逃出來了
-Troy! You made it, man!
- Conrad!
我就知道是你
I thought that was you.
你死到哪裡去了？
Where the fuck have you been?
康拉德
Conrad!
你穿的是什麼？
什麼？
-What are you wearing?
- What?
這是什麼衣服？
What is this?
這是伊拉克人給我的外套
Oh, it's a suit jacket.
The Iraqis gave it to me.
你穿這樣我都認不出來了
還蠻合身的
是啊
-I didn't recognize you in it.
-It fits all right, right?
契夫，快來幫忙
-Yeah.
-Hey, chief! We need your help!
我沒事
- I』m okay.
他被擊中哪裡？
- Where's he hit?
子彈穿過去了
我想應該就在鎖骨上方
It』s in and out. I think
it's just above his collarbone.
上帝呢？
Where's the Jesus fire?
他正在保佑你，你不會有事的
It』s all around you right now.
You're gonna be all right.
- I』m going to hell.
我會下地獄的
-You're gonna be all right, man.
你不會有事的
You're gonna be fine.
你能不能帶我到神廟去
洗清我的罪惡？
Can you take me to a shrine that gives you
comfort and erases the bad things you did?
你今天做了正確的抉擇
-Hey. We made the right choice today.
- Shh, shh.
別再提神廟的事了
你不會有事的
You stop with that shrine shit.
Everything'll be okay.
真的嗎？
當然是真的
You think so?
-I know so!
我們要快點離開這裡
We're getting out of here. Hey, major!
少校，你能不能來幫幫…
Would you please fucking help--?
該死的
Goddamn it!
特洛？
Troy.
怎麼了？
What's the matter, man?
你能呼吸嗎？
Can you breathe?
他的胸腔裡充滿了空氣
壓迫到肺部
There's air in his chest.
It』s crushing his lung.
這樣好一點了嗎？
-Does that feel better, man?
Mm-hm.
好點了嗎？
-That feel better?
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
他死了
He's gone.
每隔15分鐘就要放氣一次
Air pressure's gonna build up
about every 15 minutes.
打開氣門再關上
Release the valve
and close it back up.
我要這樣做多久？
我不知道
-How long can I keep doing that?
-I don't know.
如果出血不嚴重的
四，五個小時吧
你看來並沒有嚴重失血
Maybe four or five hours, if you're not
bleeding too bad. You don't seem to be.
他說過想去神廟
He said he wanted
to go to one of those shrines.
他是當真的嗎？
Did he mean that?
他是這麼說的
That's what he told me.
我們可以帶他到伊朗的庫姆去
Qum in Iran. We can take him with us.
那就帶他去吧
Then take him.
好，帶他去
All right. We'll take him there.
爸爸
我們在裡面找到無線電
已經幫你設定好了
We found a radio inside.
You're hooked for that call, major.
波羅，我是貝爾小白兔
Bolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
我們會坐牢的
We're going to jail.
不會的
波羅，我是貝爾小白兔
No, we're not. Bolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
這是波羅，請說
你在哪裡？
-This is Bolo. Come in.
-Where are you?
離軍營兩公里處
About two clicks outside of camp.
我們準備要到薔薇道
We're ready for that briar patch.
我只想知道我們要上哪兒去
-Ma'am, please. I』m transmitting code here!
別吵，我正在想辦法解讀密碼
-I wanna find out where we're going.
你懂了嗎，波羅？
應該吧
-You got me, Bolo?
-I think so.
薔薇道是誰負責的？
Who handles the briar patch?
是你
-You do.
-Oh, okay.
如果一切順利的話
塔兒寶貝就要到薔薇道去
Tar Baby goes to the briar patch
if everything's okay, right?
不，你說反了
-No, it's the other way around.
-Right.
對不起，長官，我忘了密碼
I』m sorry, sir. I don't remember
how the code goes.
我需要四輛卡車和一輛吉普車
I need four personnel trucks
and a Humvee.
這恐怕有點困難
That's a pretty tall order
for a secret operation, sir.
告訴我的朋友提伯
每一名駕駛都會拿到十萬元
Talk to my friend Teebaux.
Each driver will get 100K.
貝爾小白兔的位置
在北方239處
Brer Rabbit at 239 north.
別忘了帶急救箱來
還有那個記者
Add one medevac pack to the order.
Make sure you bring the reporter.
沒問題，給我兩小時
Roger. Give me two hours.
這是你的，小心藏好
把黃金埋好，契夫
Bury those real good, chief.
們帶這些人越過國界後
再想辦法來拿這些黃金
After we take these people to the border,
we'll figure out a way to get it out of here.
他太太說他在北方223
但現在那個碉堡空無一人
Two-two-three north is the position his wife
called in. There's an empty bunker.
派直升機到附近去巡邏
Task air recon to cover
223 north to the border.
準備好直升機隨時待命
如果他們在那裡
應該很容易找到
I'll put choppers on standby.
-If they're there, they won't be hard to find.
知道了，長官
All the way, sir.
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
不是我，幫拜隆注射嗎啡
It』s not me.
Barlow could use some morphine.
有人去照顧他了
讓我來看看你的傷
They've got him.
Let's see about you first.
你們找到黃金了嗎？
沒有，不過救了很多人
-Did you get the gold?
- No, but we helped a lot of people.
現在我們要想辦法
送他們過邊境
Right now we have to get them
over the border.
若是沒人保護，他們必死無疑
你會被逮捕的
-They'll be killed without our protection.
-They're gonna bust you for that.
你只管報導這件事
咱們靜觀其變
Then cover it and see what happens.
Hey.
你真的不跟我們一塊兒走？
-You sure you're not coming with us?
-No.
不，我要留下繼續作戰
I will stay here to fight Saddam.
祝你好運
Good luck.
坐好，我們很快就要出發了
Sit down. We're gonna pull out fast, okay?
坐好，我們就要出發了
Everybody sit down. We're pulling off.
華特，你認識他們嗎？
-Walter, did you meet everybody?
-Walter, this is Kaied.
華特，這是卡伊德
Hi, Kaied.
你打算怎麼做？
What are you thinking?
我們護送他們通過伊拉克關卡
確定他們平安無事後再回來
We walk them past
the Iraqi soldiers. Make sure they're safe.
We walk back to the trucks
and we get out of here.
開始吧
All right, let's do it!
不准帶槍，只有美軍才能拿槍
No guns. Only American soldiers
carry guns.
We are just now about....
拍到了嗎？
We're getting it now? We're about
25 yards from an Iraqi checkpoint...
我們目前在位於伊拉克關卡
25碼處，對面就是伊朗
...heading into Iran.
我們即將要越過邊境進入伊朗
We are just about to move across
the zone up into the Iranian border.
這裡到處都是鐵絲網
一行人有男女老幼
It』s a barbed-wire point.
We have men, women and children here...
這群伊拉克難民
就要進入伊朗了
...assumed to be Iraqi refugees
crossing over into Iran.
叫他們好好照顧康拉德
我會的
-Make sure they take care of Conrad.
-I will.
現場有許多伊拉克士兵
--ally of the United States
would be not an ally of the United States.
We did see a lot of Iraqi soldiers.
They are here, up in bunkers.
大家不要走散了
Keep in a tight group.
這似乎是某種檢查站
They're going through
some kind of checkpoint.
這已經違反了美國的政策
This is a violation of American policy.
美國已經取消了對難民的援助
The United States has
withdrawn its support.
停機再拍
-Okay. Let's cut and go again.
- Okay.
Officially supported by
the United States, they are refugees now...
...um, trying to escape
from Saddam Hussein--
The refugees are 150 yards
from the border of Iran.
Uh, the Americans here are not supposed
to be escorting anyone across the border....
你們不假外出
並違反了美國政策
You are AWOL, and you
are in violation of American policy.
你們已經被逮捕了
You are under arrest.
動作快
Double-time. Let's go!
我們能在他們
阻止我們之前過去的
We can make it before they stop us.
--to make it across the border
before the Americans land and stop them.
Come on. Move, move!
快逮捕他們
帶他們離開難民營
Arrest them. Get them away
from those refugees.
快跑
Let's go!
快來
Come here. Come here.
把手給我，小心
Give me your hand.
Give me your hand. Come on.
-Come on.
- Watch out! Unh!
你被逮捕了
讓我帶這些人過去
You're under arrest!
-Let me just help these people get across!
不
讓我帶她過去
Let me get her over! Ah!
-Let me get her over!
-Wait! Wait!
等等，讓他們過去
Just let them get over first! Wait!
我要能伸手轉動氣門才行
I need to reach this valve in my chest.
你們快讓他們過去
Look what's happening!
Just let them get over!
求求你們讓他們過去
你們不能幫助他們
Help these people get across
and I'll go with you!
讓我帶他們過去
我就跟你們回去
Let me get them across,
and I'll go right with you.
跟我們來
Let's go. You're coming with me!
-Wait. Wait.
我們不幫他們的話
他們會被殺的
They'll get slaughtered
if we don't help them across!
你們為何這麼做？
他們會被殺的
Why you doing this, man?
They gonna kill them!
難民沒有辦法成功越過邊境
他們被…
The refugees are not crossing
the border. They have been rounded up....
讓他們過去
- Just let them get over!
- Not our mission!
這不是我們的任務
你不屬於這裡
You don't belong here!
你是怎麼回事？
你不該這麼想的
What is the matter?
You ought to know better!
這不是我們的問題，你懂嗎？
We're not involved in this problem,
Major Gates. Understand?
你不假外出，你被逮捕了
You're AWOL, and you're under arrest!
你要讓他們殺這些人嗎？
這是不對的
Are you gonna let them
kill those people? It』s not right, Ron.
他們被逮捕了
我不能呼吸了
-They're arresting them.
- I can't breathe!
你敢耍我，你現在完了
你給我閉嘴
Hey! You fucked me, now you're fucked!
So shut your mouth!
--of American policy, major.
Do you understand?
我要放氣
快點照顧他
-I need to reach this!
-Give this man medical attention.
我不知道你在搞什麼鬼
但這不是我們的問題
We're not involved in this problem here.
少校，你太過份了
你們看他
-You're way out of line, major.
- Look at him!
我沒辦法放氣
他無法呼吸
- I can't reach the valve!
- He can't breathe!
把他的手銬在前面
-Put the cuffs in the front!
- He'll die if you don't--
他會死的…
你們先為自己著想吧
You don't worry about him!
Worry about yourself!
Damn it, Ron, cut his cuffs!
你已經被逮捕了
He can't breathe! Cut his cuffs!
這是怎麼回事？把攝影機關掉
What the hell is this?
Turn that camera off!
這個攝影機很貴耶
你在這裡做什麼？
- Hey, that's a $70,000 camera!
- What are you people doing here?
我有得到授權…
-I was authorized to be here.
- You were not authorized.
他要死了
He's gonna die!
- Why aren't you helping them?
- Because it's not our policy!
快解開他的手銬
Cut his cuffs!
我有權報導這則新聞
我取消你的授權
-I should tell this story!
-Out of the pool!
狗屎
你滾吧
-Bullshit!
-You're done!
我們只想幫他們而已
他們離邊境不到一百尺
All we had to do was help them.
It was less than 100 feet.
我們找到黃金了
We got the gold.
什麼？
What?
我們找到科威特的金條
鬼扯
-The Kuwaiti bullion. We've got it.
- Bullshit.
你看那個袋子，把袋子給我
去拿袋子
-Hold that bag. Give me that bag!
-Get the bag.
你們拿到多少？
2300萬
-How much do you have?
-Twenty-three million.
在哪裡？
-Where's it at?
- No.
不行，先讓他們過去
Get those people over first.
是他們幫我們找到的
They helped us find it, Ron.
我們跟他們說好了
We made a deal. It』s a soldier's honor.
事關軍人的榮譽
不能言而無信
You can't fuck them now.
把黃金還給科威特
解救難民，你會升將軍的
Come on. Return the gold.
Save some refugees. Get that star.
走吧，道格
Let's go, Doug.
這裡是誰作主？
Who's in charge here?
你們被捕了
將會受到軍法審判
You're under arrest.
You'll be court-martialed...
而且還要帶我們去找黃金
...and you'll show us
where that bullion is right now.
「艾奇，特洛
和契夫光榮退伍」
「這一切都歸功於
愛德安娜的報導」
「契夫辭掉了機場的工作
轉而和艾奇共事」
「艾奇成為好萊塢的軍事顧問」
「拜隆在加州經營地毯生意」
「伊拉克將黃金還給科威特」
「但宣稱其中部份不知去向」